Guide to the Stan Steiner Papers, ca. 1940-1987 M0700
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stan Steiner Papers
ca. 1940-1987
M0700
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
69.0 Linear feet
Scope And Content
The Steiner Papers include the personal and professional papers of Stan Steiner covering the time period from 1940 -1987 and occupy 69 linear feet. They document the personal and intellectual activities of a writer, a social historian, a moralist, a folklorist, an anecdotalist, and a myth-teller. His writings-some twenty books and countless articles-are a continuing search for vanishing cultures and the histories of forgotten people, specifically of the American West. To that end, Steiner wrote about Native Americans, the Chinese who helped build the West, Mexican Americans, New Mexico and New Mexicans, ranchers, farmers, cowboys, and Islanders. His goal was to disabuse his readers of stereotypes and misinformed images of the West by telling the complicated, nuanced, and elemental stories of these people in their own words, what Steiner called "testimonials." His manuscripts provide multiple draft copies of many of these testimonies as well as typed manuscripts and photostats of typed drafts and published works by Steiner.
Comprising 138 manuscript boxes, the papers are also a valuable trove of clippings and ephemera in the post-War era, documenting everything from right-wing organizations and social movements to Native American tribes and land policy, to the farm worker movements. These interests carry over into Steiner's correspondence and audiotapes, as well, including fairly extensive documentation of correspondence with such notables as Vine Deloria and Cesar Chavez, among others.
Steiner once wrote, "the roots of America, which are its true heritage and will be its only salvation, are what I seek in my work. For these are my roots. And in seeking and finding them there is joy and peace. There is no other." This collection documents Steiner's lifetime of seeking.
Biography
Stan Steiner was born on January 1, 1925, son of Bernard and Regina Storch Steiner of Brooklyn. After attending the University of Wisconsin for a year, Steiner hitchhiked West from New York in 1945 and began a forty year love affair with the people and places of the American West. The center of his personal and working life until his death was the reevaluation of the history of the West from a Western perspective. This took the form of his many books, from his earliest The Last Horse (1961) to the posthumous publication, edited by Emily Skretny Drabanski, of The Waning of the West (1989).Along the way, Steiner's wrote several seminal works, among them The New Indians (1968), La Raza: The Mexican Americans (1969), The Tiguas: Lost Tribe of City Indians (1972), The Islands: The World of the Puerto Ricans (1974), The Vanishing White Man (1976), Fusang: The Chinese who Built America (1979), Spirit Woman: The Diaries of Bonita Wa Wa Calachaw Nunez (editor, 1980), The Ranchers (1980, rev. 1985), and Dark and Dashing Horsemen (1981).
Steiner was a member of the Western Writers of America, the Chinese Historical Society of America, and the Western History Association. He was also a founding member of the National Association for Lawman and Outlaw History and the founder and president of the Writers' Cooperative of Santa Fe. He was the recipient of the 1971 Ainsfield Wolf Award from the Saturday Review for La Raza, the 1973 and 1977 Golden Spur Awards from the Western Writers of America for The Tiguas and The Vanishing White Man. Steiner also received a National Endowment grant in 1983. He taught at many colleges and universities throughout the United States and Europe.
Stan Steiner died in 1987. He is survived by his wife, Vera John-Steiner, the Presidential Professor of Linguistics and Education, University of New Mexico and his three children, Suki, Sandor, and Paul.
Provenance:
Donative purchase from Vera John-Steiner, 1994
Access Restrictions:
None.
Series Arranegment Note
Series I. Subject Files Subject Files make up the bulk of the collection. Steiner's clippings, notes, articles, and ephemera are arranged roughly following Steiner's own organization. For clarity, however, primary groupings have been articulated. These groupings have been organized alphabetically. Series II. Correspondence The Correspondence Series is organized into three primary groupings. The bulk of this series is organized chronologically. The second group is an alphabetical collection of correspondence related to the production of his various books, including correspondence with his publishers and fan notes. Finally, the third group of correspondence is general correspondence arranged alphabetically. Series III. Manuscripts by Steiner Steiner's manuscripts, notes on his manuscripts, and collected ephemera related to his manuscripts are gathered here alphabetically by title. Following the provenance of the collection, we have preserved the working titles Steiner gave to his manuscripts. For example, manuscript drafts of The Spirit Woman are available under S and N, following Steiner's working title: The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw. The manuscripts are arranged alphabetically. Series IV. Manuscripts by Others Manuscripts by others are arranged alphabetically. Series V. Notebooks Steiner's notebooks are arranged chronologically. Series VI. Reviews Reviews are arranged alphabetically by title. Series VII. Business Files Business Files are arranged alphabetically. Series VIII. Audiovisual Materials Audiovisual materials are arranged into three groups by format: audiocassettes, reel-to-reel tapes, and motion pictures. Within the formats, the materials are arranged alphabetically by title of Steiner's work followed by Steiner's own notation. Steiner's organization of the materials for each work has been preserved. Series IX. Clippings Clippings are a collection of miscellany left disorganized at Steiner's death. They have been organized into basic groupings which follow the organization of the subject files. Series X. Lectures and Academe Series 10 is organized alphabetically. Series XI. Publications Publications are organized alphabetically. Series XII. Steiner Library The Steiner Library is only a container listing. These volumes can be found in Stanford University Libraries stacks.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Subject Files
  - American West
    - Banking: Western Styles n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Boom Towns [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Boom Towns [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes: Kaiparowits New Town Study II, Kane County, Utah
    - The cows n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Low and high tech n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Oregon n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ranching and Farming: financial crisis n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ranching and Farming: government n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ranching and Farming: history n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ranching and Farming: way of life n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The rodeos and cowboys n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - The vigilantes n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Western Jews n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arts and Letters
    - The arts 1946 Mar. 6 -1962 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Asian Culture n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Japanese Culture 1954 -1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - New Chinese Literature 1943 July -1958 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Indian Culture 1944 June 6 -Dec. 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - South American Culture 1957 Dec. 9 -21; n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - England 1940 Mar. -1959 Sept. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - France 1940 Sept. -1958; n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Germany 1944 Aug. -1956 June (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Ireland 1955 -1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Italy 1955 -1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Scandinavia 1942 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Spain 1942 -1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Eastern Europe 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Czechoslovakia 1945 -1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Censorship: Newspapers 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Censorship: Movies 1946 -1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Censorship: Television and radio 1947 -1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Censorship: Books 1943 -1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Film: Financial Control 1946 -1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Film: Hollywood 1947 -1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Film: History 1945 -1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Film: Making of 1945 -1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Film: Censorship 1943 -1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Film: Worldwide 1946 -1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Theater: The theater 1943 -1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Theater: Economics of the theater 1945 -1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Theater: Off-Broadway Theater 1943 -1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Theater: Worldwide 1955 -1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Theater: Theater Strike 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Theater: the industry 1945 -1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Literature: The Antis 1942 -1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Literature: The Avant-garde 1955 -1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Literature: Book Clubs 1943 -1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Literature: Civil War n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Literature: Comic Books 1955 -1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Literature: European Ex's and Anti's 1941 -1951 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Literature: Ex-Communists [Fast, Howard M.] 1944 -1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Literature: Existentialists 1942 -1956 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Literature: Fascist literature: USA 1941 -1946 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Literature: Fascist literature: worldwide 1941 -1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Literature: Form and content 1944 -1950 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Literature: Hacks and hacking [Hack, Pulp, and Slick] n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Literature: Illiteracy and literacy 1946 -1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Literature: the industry 1947 -1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Literature: the intellectuals and Vietnam 1959 -1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Literature: language 1959 -1966 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Literature: Literature and Marxism 1943 -1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Literature: Literature and Art 1967 -1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Literature: Madison Avenue 1954 -1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Literature: McCarthyism and Literature 1946 -1956 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Literature: the Midwest [Ernest Hemingway and Sinclair Lewis] 1944 -1957 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Literature: Naturalism 1942 -1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Literature: The New Conservatives n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Literature: New Criticism 1950 -1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Literature: New Englanders 1954 -1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Literature: obscenity and literature 1944 -1960 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Literature: The Old American Renaissance 1943 -1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Literature: paperbacks 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Literature: poetry 1942 -1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Literature: poetry and society 1943 -1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Literature: realism 1943 -1960 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Literature: revisionism and literature 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Literature: the Robber Barons 1941 -1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Literature: Romanticism and Idealism 1936 -1951 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Literature: the Southerners 1943 -1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Literature: Trotskyism and Literature 1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Literature: the Wild West 1944 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Literature: the writer 1950s (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Literature: writers and the scientists 1944 -1955 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Literature: writers and war 1942 -1957 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Literature: writers' organizations 1941 -1960 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Literature: writers and politics 1943 -1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Literature: Yankee revolution 1943 -1957 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Literature: Zen Buddha and Bohemia 1959 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Culture and Poverty dialogue n.d. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Music and Dance: Music 1947 -1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Music and Dance: Music, Classical 1942 -1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Music and Dance: Music, Jazz 1938 -1958 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Music and Dance: Music, Popular 1944 -1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Music and Dance: Music, Folksong 1943 -1964 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Music and Dance: Dance, Classical 1947 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Music and Dance: Dance, Modern and Musical 1946 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Television: the industry 1955 -1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Television: the sponsors 1954 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Television: writing 1956 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Television: acting and directing 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Television: censorship 1954 -1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Television and radio 1946 -1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Winston-Salem Arts Council n.d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Criminology
    - Criminology 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Delinquency: New York City 1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Delinquency: USA 1936 -1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Delinquency: USSR 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Delinquency: worldwide 1958 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Delinquency and housing 1944 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Delinquency and racism 1944 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Delinquency and war hysteria 1958 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Juvenile Delinquency: pre war and war n.d. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Juvenile Delinquency: statistics n.d. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Neuro-psychiatry: general 1940s (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Neuro-psychiatry: Freudianism 1943 -1947 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Neuro-psychiatry: USSR 1945 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - New York Youth Board [1 of 2] 1956 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - New York Youth Board [2 of 2] 1956 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Police Youth Work 1958 -1967 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Prisons and rehabilitation 1948 -1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - The FBI 1958 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Reform schools and prisons n.d. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Slums and discrimination 1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - The Syndicates n.d. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Work camps 1958 -1959 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Education
    - Bilingualism [1 of 2] 1965 -1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Bilingualism [2 of 2] 1965 -1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Education: general 1948 -1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Education: general 1966 -1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Education: general n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Education: fees 1947 -1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Education: female n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Education: militarization 1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Education: racism 1949 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Education: schools 1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Education: Teachers conditions 1948 -1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Education: Teaching methods 1958 -1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Higher Education: general 1947 -1957 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Higher Education: quotas 1947 -1948 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - New, New Left [American Multiversities and student radicals] [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - New, New Left [American Multiversities and student radicals] [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 15)
      includes: "The revolt of the Multiversities," TMs
    - New, New Left [American Multiversities and student radicals] [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
      TMs, 15 pp.; TMs, 20 pp.
    - Student movement 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Tlatelolco School, Denver n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Witch-hunts of students 1947 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Witch-hunts of teachers 1947 -1954 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Environment
    - Bird and beast conversation n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - The doomsayers n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Drought Cycle of the 1970s 1970s (Box 5, Folder 23)
      Borchert, John R. "The Dustbowl in the 1970s," Annals of AAG.--Vol. 61, no. 1 (1971 Mar.)
    - Ecology: Asia n.d. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Ecology: Europe n.d. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Ecology: Socialist n.d. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Environmental Defense Fund n.d. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Environmentalists n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Hunting and fishing n.d. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Pesticides and Chemicals 1976 Mar. 6 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      "Pesticides in the Food Chain," The Nation.
    - REERIO [Regional Environmental Education, Research, and Improvement Organization, New Mexico] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Trees 1970 -1973 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Womb control: Zero and Minus-Zero Population 1972 -1973 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Corporations n.d. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Corporations: ARCO [Anderson, Robert O.] 1977 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Corporations: ITT n.d. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Corporations: Western Bancorporation n.d. (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Environment -- Air
    - Air Pollution Medical Research conference [1 of 3] 1974 Dec. 5 -6 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Air Pollution Medical Research conference [2 of 3] 1974 Dec. 5 -6 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Air Pollution Medical Research conference [3 of 3] 1974 Dec. 5 -6 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Polluted air 1969 -1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Pollution and health 1972 -1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Environment -- Black Mesa
    - Black Mesa Defense Fund 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Black Mesa: grid system for Southwest n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Black Mesa: history 1957 -1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Black Mesa: hydrology 1957 -1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Black Mesa: Kaiparowitz Power Plant 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Black Mesa: letters 1969 -1972 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Black Mesa Navajo Plant n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Black Mesa: Peabody Coal Company and Kennecott Copper Corporation n.d. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Black Mesa: Salt River Project 1967 -1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Environment -- Energy
    - Coal: Absentee owners, foreign n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Coal gassification: Four Corners [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Coal gassification: Four Corners [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Coal gassification: Southwest Research and Information Center n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Coal gassification: Utah Internation, Inc. 1973 Feb. 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Coal patrol 1971 -1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Coal leases: Northern Cheyenne and Crow 1960 -1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Energy and Environment n.d. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Energy: mining n.d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Energy: petroleum n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Energy and the West n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Energy: Western Governors Conference 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Energy crisis [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Energy crisis [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Energy proposals of President Ford [1 of 2] 1973 Apr. 18 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Energy proposals of President Ford [2 of 2] 1974 Oct. -1975 Jan. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Federal Coal Leasing and 2,560 acre limitation n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Four Corners Commission [Leaming, George F. Summary report] 1971 Dec. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Four Corners Power Plants n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Great Sweet Grass Oils, Inc. n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Gulf Oil: Pittsburgh and Midway and Gulf minerals 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Hydroelectric energy n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Las Vegas, Nevada 1971 -1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Natural Gas n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Navajo Gassification projects 1977 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Navajo power projects [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Navajo power projects [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - New Mexico energy costs 1977 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Nuclear energy 1973 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Nuclear energy: Atomic Energy Commission 1973 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Nuclear energy: Radiation danger 1969 -1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Nuclear waste disposal n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Offshore oil n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Oil resources n.d. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Petroleum industry [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Petroleum industry [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Power industry n.d. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Power use n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Rainbow Bridge n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Shale oil n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Southwest energy study [1 of 6] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Southwest energy study [2 of 6] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Southwest energy study [3 of 6] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Southwest energy study [4 of 6] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Southwest energy study [5 of 6] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Southwest energy study [6 of 6] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Total Energy [Weaver, Jim] n.d. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Geothermal energy 1965 -1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Solar energy 1972 -1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Solar energy: "The right to sunlight" n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Solar energy: tribal n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Wind power 1971 -1973 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Tidal energy 1966 -1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - miscellaneous n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Environment -- Land
    - Bureau of Land Management 1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The desert: development n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The desert: water n.d. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Great American Desert n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Land Claims 1963 -1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      includes: "It happened on the crystaline shores of Clear Lake," TMs, 6 pp.
    - Land concepts [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Land concepts [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Land concepts [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      includes: Grossman. "It there a legal way for Indians to get their land back?" TMs, 13 pp. [unfinished Esquire piece]
    - Land concepts and values n.d. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      includes: "The people as scologists / child of nature myth," TMs, 16 pp.
    - Land resources n.d. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Land sales: development and urbanization n.d. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Land treaties n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Land use n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - National Parks and wilderness areas n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Public land: College of Idaho conference 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Tribal land right: stripmining n.d. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Environment -- Mining
    - Cerrillos mining n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Mineral depletion in the USA n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Mining Association Convention, Carlsbad 1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Montana strip mining [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Montana strip mining [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Strip mining n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Strip mining: laws n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Strip mining: methods n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Strip mining: reclamation 1971 -1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Environment -- Policy
    - Colorado Plateau Environmental Advisory Council 1970 -1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior n.d. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Energy of Life": Di Luzio n.d. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Earthcare Conference, United Nations 1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ecology elections n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Environmental Protection Agency n.d. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Hathaway, Stan: nomination for Secretary of the Interior 1975 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Hickel, Wally. "Who owns the sunset?" 1975 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Merry, Ike.: Ceremonial, Gallup, NM n.d. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Military and ecology n.d. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - MacDonald [Peter] indictments: Tucson Gas 1977 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - United Nations: ecology and energy n.d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - United States Forest Service n.d. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - United States Forest Service n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - United States Geological Survey n.d. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - United States Senate: Abourezk, James n.d. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - United States Senate: hearings 1971 May 25 -27 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - United States Weather Service n.d. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - White House: energy policy n.d. (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Environment -- States
    - Alaska 1972 -1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Alaska: native land claims [1 of 2] 1958 -1966 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Alaska: native land claims [2 of 2] 1958 -1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)